Jerry Vance Anguzu - Data Scientist & Software Engineer

anguzuvi@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/jerryvance • github.com/jerryavance • +256-753493685 • Uganda

SUMMARY

Extensive experience with applying analytical and statistical methods to model a broad range of systems from stochastic systems to large-scale data structures. My focus is to build intelligent systems using large-scale, real-world data that have real-world impact. Interested in the intersection of statistics, machine learning, and optimization, focusing primarily on the design and analysis of statistical methods for high-dimensional problems in the context of learning from data. Proven track record of programming to perform data analysis. Strong ability to collaborate and work in a team environment on multi-disciplinary projects.

EDUCATION

Massachusetts Institute of Technology - MIT ReACT / Certificate Program in Computer and Data Science

August 2020 - September 2021, Cambridge MA

Coursework: Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Complexity Theory, Stochastic & Dynamic Programming, Statistical Thinking, Monte Carlo simulations.

Kyambogo University / Bachelor of Science in Statistics

August 2017 - September 2021, Kampala-Uganda

Coursework: Multivariate methods, Stochastic processes, Numerical analysis, Probability Modeling, Bayesian Inference & Decision Theory.

RELEVANT SKILLS

Software Programming: C/C++; Python; HTML; CSS; JavaScript; PyTorch; TensorFlow; R; Tableau; Excel; GCP.

Domain: Statistics; Machine learning; Big data; Data modeling; Data visualization; Reporting.

Analytical Design and Analysis of Algorithms; Optimization; Stochastic simulation; Statistical analysis; Multi-scale modeling;

Stochastic programming; Statistical thinking; Monte Carlo simulations and modeling uncertainties; Finite element method;

Business Intelligence; Software engineering; Systems engineering; Trend analysis; A/B testing; Data analysis.

Projects Designed an Automatic Review Analyzer for sentiment analysis of product reviews; Digit Recognition with Neural

Networks to classify MNIST digits; Tackled the task of learning control policies for text-based games using Reinforcement Learning; Built a mixture model for collaborative filtering from the Netflix database to predict entries of the ratings matrix.

Language English (Full Professional proficiency); Lugbara (native); Luganda (native) ; Kiswahili (basic)

Soft skills: Teamwork; Leadership; Problem solving; Communication.

EXPERIENCE

Whitaker Peace and Development Initiative / MIT Open Learning Information Technology Lab intern

Remote-Uganda

Oct 2021 - Present

- Curating MIT open education resources (OER) to contribute to WPDI's online platform providing educational material about Peace, Entrepreneurship and ICT to the Community Learning Center's users in the Kiryandongo Refugee Settlement.
- Supporting capacity building of the WPDI Kiryandongo Community Learning Center team in producing digital educational materials and videos for the online platform through workshops and training from MIT and WPDI.

M-Kopa Remote-Uganda

Finance Data Intern Aug 2021 - Present

- Working to automate sales data validation processes using machine learning.
- Ensuring accuracy of the data input vs daily sales data for purposes of invoicing to the Uganda Revenue Authority.
- Maintaining data backup and reconciliation as part of the contingency plan.

Electoral Commission of Uganda

Kampala-Uganda

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

- Statistician (Internship)Performed statistical analysis and ensured accuracy of statistical results.
 - Collected and organized data to be uploaded into various systems.
 - Worked well with different types of people to address challenges and solve problems collaboratively.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Google Africa Developer Scholarship, Mobile Web Specialist - Andela, Pluralsight	Present
ALGS200x: Algorithmic Design and Techniques - UCSanDiegoX, edx	Aug 2021
Remote Ready - Oyster®	Apr 2021
6.00.2x: Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, edx	May 2021
6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, edx	Mar 2021
6.86x: Machine Learning with Python-From Linear Models to Deep Learning -Massachusetts Institute of Technology, edx	Dec 2020
18.6501x: Fundamentals of Statistics - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, edx	Sep 2020
Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals - Google, Coursera	May 2020
Smart Analytics, Machine Learning, and AI on GCP - Google, Coursera	May 2020
Divide and Conquer, Sorting and Searching, and Randomized Algorithms - Stanford University, Coursera	Apr 2020
Divide and Conquer, Sorting and Searching, and Kandonnized Algorithms - Stamord University, Coursera	Apr 2020

ORGANIZATIONS

MIT Refugee Action Hub - ReACT is a center at MIT to design and deploy new learning opportunities for displaced populations around the world. *Na'amal* - Partners with organisations to support refugees & vulnerable populations through skills training, mentorship & remote work placements.

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Driving • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • Engineering • Mathematics • FinTech • Entrepreneurship • Science • Athletics • Motorsport • Podcasts

LEADERSHIP, HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENTS